<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Coats and Kahvi</title>
        <description>Meredith and Scott&#39;s Adventures in Finland</description>
        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://coatsandkahvi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                <item>
                        <title>Paris (&lt;em&gt;and summer in Finland&lt;/em&gt;)</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/builldings_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/building_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/man_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/selfie_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/notredame_)2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/street_notredame.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/grafiti_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/scottandparents_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/boat_meredithandscott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/car_chez.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/lawn_people.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/flowers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/paintings_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/monalisa_sculptures.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/ceiling_kenny.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_castle.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_fountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/me_versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/scottandkenny_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/Scott_Versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/eifel+tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/eifeltower_kennyandbarb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/group_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/Eifel+tower+at+sunset.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of those who have prayed, hoped and wished for warm weather to make its way to Finland, thank you, it has.  Now if we could work on a little AC up in here, that’d be really cool (no pun intended). I am so thankful for and loving all this warm weather and sunshine that we’ve been getting, really I am.  Everyone is happy, people are out and about and picnics are happening all over the city.  It’s the best.  But when it’s 80+ outside and you have to be inside, with no AC, well let’s just say if it weren’t for the mosquitos I’d be sleeping in the forest.  When the wind blows our door closed, I sprint to prop it back open to prevent an immediate pool of sweat and suffocation.  I have my fly swatter (thanks mom) ready at all times in case one of those annoying creatures tries to sneak their way through the open windows and doors.  But I know that sooner than I care to admit the chilling winds will be back again and open windows won’t even be an option, so I’m going to turn that fan on high and keep reminding myself that it’s better than frozen eyelashes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a little over a month ago we took a trip to Paris for a week with Scott’s parents.  I’m going to blame the fact that I’m just now writing about it on the mere three weeks that I’ve spent in Joensuu since the beginning of June AND my little motivation to do anything that involves my legs sticking to a chair while staring at a computer.  Yep, that’s my excuse.  My idea of Paris was pretty much the same one that is portrayed on TV.  Beautiful, wonderful, romantic…just about everything perfect squished into one city.  There’s so much hype around the city that I thought there was no way it could live up to my (and many people’s) expectations.  But as cliché as it sounds, I did kind of fall just a little bit in love with the city.  The museums, churches and Eiffel Tower are all amazing, but what I really loved was the everyday kind of stuff.  Like the millions of cafés lining every street, filled with people enjoying the weather and good company.  And the parks, or just dots of green, for people to bring their picnics of baguettes, cheese and a bottle of wine (yes, that actually happens in real life).  Oh, and all the buildings.  I just couldn’t get enough of the white-grayish old buildings that give the city it’s relaxed, romantic feel.  It also didn’t hurt that we had near perfect weather the entire time we were there, which really makes everything better.  I don’t know what it is about the city. You can do nothing except sit at a café and people-watch, and at the end of the day you still feel like you’ve had a pretty solid day.  But that’s what’s so great about it. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/31/Paris-France.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/31/Paris-France.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Gdańsk, Poland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/boat_building_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/buildings_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/monument.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/Monument_church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/musicians_streetperformer.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/slanted_builings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up at 5:00 am, rolled out of bed, stumbled downstairs to pick up our carefully packed breakfast and began our journey to Gdańsk.  The first 2 hours on the bus were pretty silent.  Occasionally you could hear a short mumbled conversation, but for the most far it was silent, with heads bobbing up and down, trying desperately to get more sleep.  As we arrived in Gdańsk, heads began to perk up and eyes were peeled open to take in the new city.  Our first stop was a boat ride and tour of some of the historical WWII sites.  Seeing the city by boat was a fun new perspective as we watched people enjoying the warm sun and the colorful waterfront buildings pass by.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a big helping of pierogi (Polish dumplings) for lunch, we spent some time walking around the city, marveling at the beautiful churches and mesmerizing buildings.  Gdańsk is known as the capital of amber, with tons of street vendors displaying an array of jewelry made with the Baltic gold, so of course we couldn’t leave without some time spent shopping.  Our last stop, before heading back, was a quick trip to the beach on the Baltic Sea.  The beach was packed with people lounging in padded beach chairs, under umbrellas and a few brave souls who ventured out to the frigid water.  We left Gdańsk beat from the long, action-packed day, while simultaneously craving more time in the lively port town.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised with all that the city had to offer from the rich history, the cheerful old town and the lovely beaches.  I couldn’t help but think about what a perfect weekend getaway destination it would be.       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/09/Gdansk-Poland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/09/Gdansk-Poland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Toruń, Poland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/rooftops.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/rainy_street.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/flowershop_rain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/castles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/building_angel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/angel_roof.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/balcony_flags.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/classroom.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/colored_buildings_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/market.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/minibeer.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/flower_copernicus.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/outthewindow.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/streets_two.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, YAY we’re back in Joensuu!  The past month has been full of fun times and great memories, but I sure was ready to be back in my own bed.  The first two weeks of the trip I was in Toruń, Poland working with students from three other countries on an intensive summer course.  The topic was building intercultural awareness in teaching English as a foreign language.  We arrived late Sunday night after a 4.5 hour train to Helsinki, 2 hour flight to Warsaw and then a 4 hour bus ride to Toruń.  Then early Monday morning we were up for the beginning of ten long days in class (don&amp;#39;t worry, we managed to squeeze in some time for fun).  There were nine other students from UEF that went on the trip, so I got to make some pretty great friends as well.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about Poland.  Go there.  Seriously, it’s such an interesting, beautiful country filled with so much history.  In Toruń there was a wonderful Old Town filled with ornate, colorful buildings that I could just stare at all day (maybe that’s why I have so many pictures of them).  And because we were studying with Polish students, we also got to learn a lot about Polish culture. For instance, what I would call ‘lunch’ they refer to as ‘dinner’ and it’s eaten at around 1 pm.  The meal generally consists of three courses and starts with a soup, then you have the entrée, which is usually some sort of meat and potatoes, and then a dessert.  Later you have ‘supper’ which is around 6 pm and is generally some form of sandwich.  Being in Poland, we followed the same daily meal schedule.  I always find it interesting to learn about other food cultures.  I think you can tell a lot about a culture from how and what they eat.  We also learned a little about Nicolaus Copernicus, who is the pride and joy of Toruń.  There&amp;#39;s a statue of him in the center of the old town and the univeristy, where we were studying, is named after him.  As our welcoming gift, we all got Nicolaus Copernicus zip drives!   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we were in class a lot, there were still plenty late nights hanging out with new friends from Spain, France, Poland (and of course, Finland).  That was the best part of the trip.  Just talking, laughing and being with those people.  After two weeks of cramming in a ridiculous amount of work and play, I was completely worn out, but it was so so worth it.           &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/03/Torun-Poland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/03/Torun-Poland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Market Day</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/booths.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/flags.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/fish.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/leaves.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/chef_salmon.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/romeo_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mother Nature really pulled through this weekend.  Clear skies and rising temperatures made for a pretty perfect market day.  The first traditional fish market in Joensuu was held on Saturday where vendors sold fresh fish, homemade jams, wooden handicrafts and lots of other goodies.  We sat outside eating our crucified salmon and all our winter woes were forgotten.  There’s just something about outdoor markets that makes me smile.  I don’t know if it’s the warm weather that generally accompanies them, the smell of freshly cooked food or the community feel to the whole event, but it sure makes for a solid afternoon.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t want to disappoint anyone by skipping over the weather report, so here it goes, today was &lt;strong&gt;hot&lt;/strong&gt;.  I know you’re thinking, &lt;em&gt;you mean like you only had to wear one pair of wool socks kind of weather?&lt;/em&gt;  Nope.  Like shorts and sandals and sunbathing kind of weather.  Seriously.  The city was crawling with people soaking it all up.  I’d say about 50% of the people we passed were carrying ice cream cones (including me).  Every pier we passed on the way home was occupied by picnic-ers.  We bought a fan.  These are the signs of summer.  I’m still a bit hesitant to leave the house without gloves and a jacket, I just feel naked without them, but I’m sure pretty soon I won’t be giving them a second thought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and the last, &lt;em&gt;but definitely not the least&lt;/em&gt;, glorious thing to report, we ate barbecue today.  I’m not talking about Finnish BBQ, which really just involves cooking anything over an open fire, I mean like a legit pulled pork sandwich.  In the middle of downtown Joensuu, there is a man from Florida that cooks up some serious Texas-style barbecue.  I was tempted to run around with my sandwich introducing everyone to the deliciousness of real BBQ so they could see what they’d been missing out on all this time.  Instead, I sat in the scorching sun with BBQ sauce all over my face and for a moment I felt like I was back in Texas.  Funny how food can do that to you (&lt;em&gt;or is that just me?&lt;/em&gt;)                    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/18/Market-Saturday.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/18/Market-Saturday.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>May Day</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/Balloons.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/People_balloons.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/Lake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/church_pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/stage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/VappuuPicnic.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyvää Vappua! Happy May Day! We&amp;#39;ve had quite the busy week over here celebrating.  Vappu is the second biggest holiday celebration in Finland (first being Midsummers).  I&amp;#39;ve never seen so many people out in Joensuu – I didn&amp;#39;t even know that many people lived here.  Although May Day is officially May 1st, the festivities ran throughout the entire week.  We started the week with the &lt;em&gt;flying flags&lt;/em&gt; event at the university, where we each wrote about our experiences in Finland on the back of our country&amp;#39;s flag.  Then we let them go together to demonstrate what the exchange students bring to Finland.  The next day we went on a bus tour of Eastern Finland.  We stopped at various places to explore and socialize, then we were back on the bus to the next stop.  On Vappu Eve there was a parade of students from the university to an island across town.  In Finland, all students have different colored jumpsuits according to their major.  They collect badges from different events that they take part in and cover their jumpsuits in them.  On special occasions (Vappu being one) all the people that have graduated from basic school (high school) wear their graduation caps proudly.  It&amp;#39;s really a big deal to be able to show off your cap.  After the parade, people gather at the island where there is music playing and they hang out with their friends.  People continue partying wayyy into the night, since the next day is a national holiday.  On the actual day (May 1st), everyone gathers in the city center where there are vendors selling May Day balloons and streamers, a vintage car parade and plenty of socializing.  As the day goes on, people begin to make their way  to the island to have a picnic with their friends and family.  Although it wasn&amp;#39;t exactly picnic weather, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m talking 35 degrees&lt;/em&gt;, we enjoyed spending time eating with our friends.  All the Vappuu activities may have gotten in the way of a little school work this week, but I can&amp;#39;t miss out on the culture, right?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that every time I start to talk about the &lt;em&gt;amazzzzingly&lt;/em&gt; wonderful weather in Finland, it comes back to haunt me.  Remember last week when I was raving about how perfect the weather was... well I take it back.  It has snowed at least three days since then.  &lt;em&gt;Not cool, Finland, not cool.&lt;/em&gt;  They say that warm weather is coming, but I&amp;#39;ll believe it when I see it.    Yesterday we spent a good amount of time outside, when it suddenly began to snow.  I looked at a Finnish guy near us with what I&amp;#39;m sure was a “&lt;em&gt;you&amp;#39;ve got to be kidding me&lt;/em&gt;” face.  And his apt response was, “&lt;em&gt;It&amp;#39;s Finland, what can I say?&lt;/em&gt;”.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/04/May-Day.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/04/May-Day.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>It&#39;s Spring</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/04.27.2014/boat_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/04.27.2014/scott_laying_on_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y&amp;#39;all, it&amp;#39;s spring in Finland!  From the day we got back it&amp;#39;s been nothing but beautiful weather.  I&amp;#39;m talking sunny days and warm (relatively) temperatures.  I haven&amp;#39;t worn a scarf since we&amp;#39;ve been back.  Yesterday my legs were exposed to the Finnish sun for the first time since September.  Okay, really it was just my ankles, but it was BIG.  It&amp;#39;s been so nice that it&amp;#39;s making it hard to stay inside and concentrate on school work because I just want to live outside.  Picnics are seriously calling my name.  I want to picnic every meal.  Even though this seems like a huge change from the below 30 degree weather when we left in early April, the biggest adjustment has been the sun.  Right now the sun rises before 5:00 am and sets after 9:00 pm.  Which, don&amp;#39;t get me wrong, is amaaaaazzzing, but it&amp;#39;s completely throwing us off.  We brought back some black out curtains because, even before we left, the sun was waking us up at 5 every morning.  They work like magic.  The only problem is it is so dark in our room that it makes waking up harder (I&amp;#39;m still going to blame it on the jet lag though).  This weekend we slept till 11 one morning and 10 the next.  I don&amp;#39;t remember the last time I&amp;#39;ve done that.  Then the situation at night is the opposite.  It is so bright outside until about 8:45 that we don&amp;#39;t even start thinking about dinner until at least 8:00.  The sun is turning us into the Spaniards and Greeks.  Last night we ate at 10:00!  And this is not even the most sun we will get.  In June we&amp;#39;ll have 20 hours of sunlight!  Talk about a huge change – in December I was coming out of class at 3:00 to total darkness and now the sun is barely setting when it&amp;#39;s time for me to go to bed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I will be stuck inside some, finishing up these last few weeks of school, there will be plenty of time carved out to enjoy the outdoors.  This week is Vappuu (May Day) and we have lots of fun activities planned!    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/04/27/its-spring.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/04/27/its-spring.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Sunday afternoon bike rides</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.10.2014/walking_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sundays are pretty great days.  I hesitate to call them my favorite because Friday and Saturday put up a pretty good fight, so let&amp;#39;s just say they&amp;#39;re top 3.  Even though Sundays back home looked different than they do now, I still treasure my Sundays.  I&amp;#39;ve started a new tradition of making breakfast on the weekends.  It&amp;#39;s one of the best ideas I&amp;#39;ve had.  I love breakfast.  Like love LOVE breakfast.  Hands down my favorite meal.  Lunch and dinner got nothing on breakfast.  The problem is I am usually so hungry in the morning that I can barely pour my cereal fast enough, much less spend any significant amount of time conjuring up a meal that involves turning on the stove.  But in some crazy miraculous change of events, I&amp;#39;ve found a way.  Maybe it&amp;#39;s the promise of something extra delicious to chow down on, &lt;em&gt;who knows&lt;/em&gt;.  This mouth-watering occasion is one reason that I long for Sundays and now I&amp;#39;ve added another.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ride our bikes a lot.  And although they seldom go a day without turning their wheels, they rarely get ridden for pure enjoyment.  Most of the time they are just a means of transportation.  It&amp;#39;s such a shame.  These tired old machines never get to have any fun.  But we have vowed to change that.  A bike ride has now been added to our Sunday routine.  We decided not to wait until the sun comes out and the flowers are blooming to start because, quite frankly, that could be a while.  Today was day 1.  We rode our bikes down our mostly clear sidewalks until there was no more sidewalk.  When the sidewalk ends and you look to the left, you can see a small hill.  The forest lets you see just enough to marvel at it, but keeps some of its treasures hidden to draw you in closer.  We&amp;#39;d been to this spot before when you could see the dirt on the ground, so we wanted to to see what it looked like in its winter attire.  The icy trails forced us to leave our bikes behind, but the small trek through the woods was worth it.  An undiscovered path is on the agenda for next Sunday.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/09/Sunday-afternoon-bike-rides.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/09/Sunday-afternoon-bike-rides.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>All it takes is a piece of cake</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/street.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/buildings_street.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/green+building.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/book_shelves.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/books.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.07.2014/archway_girl.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of talking about how done I am with this weather and how the weather in Helsinki was equally as miserable (if not worse) and how all the pictures of warm places with people in anything less than a winter coat and boots are making me crazy... I&amp;#39;m going to tell you about all the food we ate on our trip.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s pretty much what we did.  We ate.  So let&amp;#39;s first talk about the Mexican-style brunch.  Anything with a slight resemblance to Mexican food and we&amp;#39;re there.  I will admit now that it was worth the cold, wet walk over.  I&amp;#39;m not even sure what some of the items were exactly, but I will tell you they were delicious and spicy, just how I like it.  Then there was Fafa&amp;#39;s.  Giant falafals in fluffy pita bread.  I got the one with pesto and goat cheese.  Yes, &lt;em&gt;to die for&lt;/em&gt;.  The restaurant was out of this old, white van look-alike.  Think stationary food truck.  There were only about 15 seats total, which makes you feel like you snagged a highly coveted spot.  It&amp;#39;s located in the middle of a bunch of office buildings, so you would never find it just walking around, but we were on a mission.  Then there&amp;#39;s my favorite, well favorites, which were all the cute cafés around town.  The one that really took the cake (I&amp;#39;ll tell you more about that in a moment) was this small little café tucked in a corner, down the street from where we were staying.  Give me a cinnamon roll or croissant with a cappuccino for breakfast and I am a happy camper.  It&amp;#39;s one of those places that would be very dangerous to live by because it would be calling  my name every time I passed by.  In fact it did one of the days we were there.  We were going to walk by on the way back to our apartment so I took that as an opportunity to try a slice of cake.  I&amp;#39;m not a huge cake person, well really just not a huge frosting person, but these cakes were of the homemade variety.  They were different every day.  &lt;em&gt;Who eats cake in the middle of the day with no special occasion&lt;/em&gt;, you ask?  I asked myself the same question, after my teeth were already covered in chocolatey goodness, and I decided the answer was that people who live by this place do.  So as I was temporarily living there for a couple of days, I should do as the locals do.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly we needed some comforting from the weather.  And we found it in the food.  It really is amazing how much the weather dictates what you eat.  So to survive this next month of on and off rain/snow/sleet, we&amp;#39;re going to be making some really comforting food around here.  Starting with our favorite Moroccan-style stew.  Mmmmm...I can already taste those melt-in-your-mouth sweet potatoes infused with the sweet sweet spices.              &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/07/all-it-takes-is-a-piece-of-cake.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/07/all-it-takes-is-a-piece-of-cake.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Ski Break</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.01.2014/bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have Spring break, we have Ski break.  Both occur in March and are all about taking a little time from school to enjoy the outdoors.  Other than that, they have nothing in common.  Spring break is swimming pools, swim suits and sun.  Ski break is snow ball fights, snow shoeing and of course, skiing.  (Ok, I just noticed that they all start with S&amp;#39;s too...so there&amp;#39;s that).  I&amp;#39;m all about these sorts of icy outings and I feel like I&amp;#39;ve been a pretty darn good sport about the winter, but I&amp;#39;m going to go ahead and call it.  I can not fool my Texas brain into thinking we&amp;#39;re still in December.  It knows better.  It knows that this is the time to start breaking out the shorts and eating outside.  This snow just isn&amp;#39;t going to do it for me anymore.  I&amp;#39;m on board for it coming back in about 8 months.  But now, it&amp;#39;s time to stop this madness.  It&amp;#39;s been real.  Needless to say, we are not headed for the slopes next week.  We&amp;#39;re boarding the train headed south.  Literally.  We&amp;#39;re going to Helsinki.  Unfortunately it&amp;#39;s not exactly beachy there either, but we&amp;#39;ll take what we can get right now.  If you could direct any heat waves that you find in this general direction, we would greatly appreciate it.          &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/01/ski-break.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/01/ski-break.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Cold Natured</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/showshoeing_wheatgrass.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/people_frozenlake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/showshoeing_icehole.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_snowmobile.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_tinytree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/branch_houses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse_licking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse_smiling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the days go by, I learn more and more about the Finnish culture.  I know that we&amp;#39;ve lived here for almost 6 months now, but it continues to fascinate me.  For one, Finns come alive in the winter.  It&amp;#39;s like someone flipped a switch and everyone suddenly sprang to life.  When the days get down to 20 or below, you can see the smiles on their faces and hear the excitement in their voices.  &lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt;, they say, &lt;em&gt;a proper winter&lt;/em&gt;!  They use words like &lt;em&gt;fresh&lt;/em&gt; to describe freezing temperatures.  I guess when winter takes up a majority of the year, you learn to embrace it.  No, they don&amp;#39;t embrace it, they &lt;em&gt;thrive&lt;/em&gt; off it.  All year they are waiting until the conditions are right for skiing, ice hockey, skating, ice fishing and all their other favorite winter activities.  They will tell you that the best sauna is the one when you can take a break from the heat to roll around in the snow (with no clothes on).  Now, I don&amp;#39;t want to make any over-generalizations about the entire population.  I have met a Finn that wasn&amp;#39;t a fan of winter, but I&amp;#39;d say those are few and far between.  Most of the time, you will find them enjoying the outdoors during these snow-covered days.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don&amp;#39;t know if I quite thrive  off these northern temperatures yet, I have learned to embrace them.  I get to try so many things that I&amp;#39;ve never done before, like snowshoeing.  The other day a group of us went on a snowshoeing trek on and around a peninsula in Joensuu.  It took a little while to get used to waddling like a duck in the shoes, but soon it came naturally.  When we got to the lake our guides told us that we were going to cross by walking &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the lake.  I was a little hesitant at first because I didn&amp;#39;t totally trust that the water was frozen and would be able to hold my weight (plus 10 other people), but Finnish people usually know what they&amp;#39;re talking about when it comes to nature, so I went for it.  In the distance there were people snowmobiling, ice fishing and generally just enjoying an afternoon on the lake.  Being completely new to all this cold weather stuff, it was still kind of crazy to think about an entire lake being frozen.  Oh, and the sun peeked through the clouds for a couple of minutes.  That&amp;#39;s enough to lift my spirit for days.  It was a great way to spend an afternoon and when I got home I was exhausted.  While we were out there I didn&amp;#39;t feel like it was strenuous, but I guess 3 hours of snowshoeing will take it out of you.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I know that everything I write about revolves around it being cold, but that pretty much sums up our lives right now.  &lt;em&gt;Cold and winter.&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/21/cold-natured.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/21/cold-natured.html</guid>
                </item>
        
</rss>