<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Coats and Kahvi</title>
        <description>Meredith and Scott&#39;s Adventures in Finland</description>
        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://coatsandkahvi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                <item>
                        <title>Bergen</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/islands.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/group_hike.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/hike_overlook.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/oldtown.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/rain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/meredith_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/trains_buses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/group_fjord.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/fjord.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/ferry_meredith_debran.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/fjord_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/mountain_bird_green.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/scott_kevin_debran_mountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/ferry_debran_kevin.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/dock.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/townonthemountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/meredithscott_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/waterfalls.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day we got to Bergen it was pouring rain and pretty darn chilly.  Scott and I came completely unprepared, with no rain jackets and barely any warm clothing.  We had gotten used to the nice warm weather we’d been having way too easily and forgotten that these places require jackets and scarfs for most of the year.  Our traveling buddies, however, came far more prepared than we did.  Which shouldn’t have come as a surprise since they’re always far more prepared than us (&lt;em&gt;that’s why we’re friends&lt;/em&gt;).  We made the decision that we weren’t going to let the rain get in our way of seeing this Norwegian city though.  After all, Bergen has over 230 days of annual rainfall (&lt;em&gt;we found out once we were there&lt;/em&gt;).  So we trudged out into the city with wet clothes and smiles on our faces (sort of).  One of the things that our host warned us about (but definitely not the most shocking) was the high cost of eating at restaurants in Norway.  Most locals cook at home to keep costs down and rarely eat out.  So we followed her advice and went to the fish market to buy our dinner.  After gathering all the supplies to make dinner, we took the short cut back to our place.  This is the other &lt;em&gt;shocking&lt;/em&gt; thing that our host warned us about.  Across the street from the apartment that we were renting, was a well known drug park.  Everyone knew it, even the police, and apparently they had made the decision to leave all the druggies be, as long as they kept to the park.  We were warned that we would see all kinds of &lt;em&gt;crrrrazy&lt;/em&gt; stuff going on in the park.  &lt;em&gt;It’s like your own private show, right outside your window,&lt;/em&gt; she explained, laughing. We all laughed with her.  Then when she left we looked at each other, completely stunned.  Not exactly the kind of welcoming we had imagined.  But then we laughed again, for real this time, and took the long way to the market.  Well on the way back it was raining, like really raining, and we were carrying heavy bags of groceries.  So we opted for the short cut through the park, after all, she assured us it was completely safe.  &lt;em&gt;Don’t look at them, walk fast, but not too fast, act like we’re talking&lt;/em&gt;…these were the things we reminded each other of before embarking on the 2 minute walk through the park.  &lt;em&gt;Ok, we’re almost there.  Which way is it?  I think it’s this way.  Wait, maybe it’s that way.  Just keep walking!&lt;/em&gt; - as we basically slid down a steep muddy hill, which was clearly not the path to our apartment.   But looking lost in the middle of the drug park was not an option, so we acted as if we needed a good challenge.  Sidewalks bore us.  We successfully made it back, after what seemed like 2 &lt;em&gt;very long&lt;/em&gt; minutes.  We earned some serious bravery points for that, I’m sure.  I mean, no big deal, we’re hardcore.                     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our first day there, mother nature pleasantly surprised us with lots of sun and very minimal rain.  I think that I can speak for the group when I say that the best part of our stay in Bergen was the day we took the ferry through the Sognefjord.  To get to the fjord we took a train and a bus through some of the most stunning landscapes I’ve ever seen.  The kind that that make it on postcards.  It was unreal.  But the ferry through the fjord was definitely the cherry on top.  The greenest greens and the bluest blues you’ve ever seen.  Waterfalls every time you turned your head.  Mountains coming straight out of the river, on both sides, decorated every so often with a tiny cluster of houses.  Better than the pictures.  It was, without a doubt, worth &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; walks through the drug park.                     &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/17/Bergen.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/17/Bergen.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Stockholm</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/island.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/guards_oldtown.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/apples_bikes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/groupphoto.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/park_boats.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/peopleswimming.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/scott_buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/over+the+water_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/sunset.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this next round of travels, not only did we have some exciting Scandinavian cities to visit, but we also had some of our favorite people join us!  We met Kevin and Debrán in Stockholm to start the trip and, despite their luggage getting lost by the airlines, it was a pretty great kickoff.  We decided that the best way to see the city (and save our feet) was to join the hordes of commuting bike riders.  On our first day with the bikes we took them exploring through one of the many islands which was, apparently, one of the &lt;em&gt;cool kid&lt;/em&gt; hangouts during the summer.  Stockholm is pretty cool like that.  They have all these random, &lt;em&gt;gigantic&lt;/em&gt; parks all over the place where you can find pretty much the entire population of the city on a nice summer evening.  So we followed suit and did our fair share of sitting, laying, picnic-ing on the grass, soaking up as much of summer as these Scandinavian countries offer.  Then we fantasized about buying one of those adorable houses on the water and going on bike rides everyday around the islands, picking fresh apples and maybe even building up the courage to swim in the frigid water. Yeah, I know, I do that everywhere I go.  I can’t help it, I like to dream.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/15/Stockholm.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/15/Stockholm.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Copenhagen &amp; Aarhus</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/sunset+bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/mom_me_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/grafetti_bike.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/castles_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/copenhagen+from+the+top.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/momtower_tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/floweres.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/me_bikepath.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/porridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/porridge_bread.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/cheers_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/houses_grafetti.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/apartments.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/momandme_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/house.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/yard_momandme.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/pier_water.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/goingdownthestairs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/rocks.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/flowers_sail.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/sailboat_bathhouse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/blackberry_mom.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/ARoS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/ARoS_inside.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denmark has definitely made its way onto my list of “places I could live”.  The food really helped give it a good shove up the list.  I still daydream about it.  Scott and I have become major porridge fans since living in Finland and Copenhagen has a restaurant dedicated SOLELY to porridge. Score! But it’s really more than just food (although that might be enough to make me move there).  Everything is just so…pretty.  They’ve really got that whole Scandinavian design thing going for them.  Copenhagen has all that you could want in a big city without feeling too big.  And when you want to escape from all the fuss of the city, well you can just have a picnic in the cemetery, like we did.  To tell you the truth, I was a little skeptical about this whole idea at first, but the first time we walked through and saw locals running, sun bathing and enjoying their lunch, I was convinced.  It’s basically a giant park.  And what better way to use such a space on a sunny afternoon, than a picnic.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people in Denmark also helped make it so wonderful.  They are so down to earth and friendly, which really worked in my favor, since I had a couple of &lt;em&gt;moments&lt;/em&gt; during our time there.  It started the first day we were in Copenhagen. After our first super delicious meal, I left my jacket (the only one I brought) at the restaurant.  We were mid-way through the Superkilen park when I realized (and panicked).  I walked just about as fast as I could, without looking like a lunatic, back to the restaurant.  Luckily, my jacket was waiting for me just inside the door.  The second time I tested the Danes was while we were walking to the canals.  On the way we decided to pop into in several boutique-y shops.  Well, I found a really nice piece of pottery and I wanted to see how much it cost.  So I picked it up.  Unfortunately there were two pieces to this particular item and I only picked up the top part.  After that, all I remember is the entire thing on the floor, in a million pieces.  (Although I did manage to see the price, which was equivalent to $100.)  First, the sweet woman working looked stunned, like she didn’t know what to do.  (Probably because nothing like that had ever happened before…oops.) Then she quickly went to clean it up and told us not to worry about it.  After helping her clean, I could not get out of the store fast enough.  The rest of the trip I had someone looking over my shoulder to make sure I wasn’t touching anything breakable, &lt;em&gt;thanks mom&lt;/em&gt;.  The last little mishap, was not so little after all.  See, I bought train tickets from Copenhagen to Aarhus. Or at least I thought I did.  And what does one do when they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they buy train tickets? Well, they get on the train.  Turns out (after three different people tried to figure out &lt;em&gt;what in the world&lt;/em&gt; was going on with our tickets) I had bought bus tickets instead.  &lt;em&gt;Whoops&lt;/em&gt;.  But we were already on the train on our way to Aarhus.  So thankfully, the super kind ticket checker let us slide.  I told you those Danes were nice.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m pretty sure that I made such a good impression on them, soon they&amp;#39;ll be begging me to move there.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/11/Copenhagen-and-Aarhus.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/11/Copenhagen-and-Aarhus.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Mom comes to Finland!</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/sailboat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/island.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/boat_flag.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/yellowflowers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/beach_birthday.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/mom_bikes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/mom_laundry.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/momandI_Suomelinna.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.05.2014/coffee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so exciting to get to show someone around where you live.  Although tons of people have seen pictures and heard stories, nothing beats seeing it in person.  There’s not many “sights” to see in Joensuu so when I was showing my mom around the city it was more like, “This is the grocery store we go to” and “Here’s the university” and “Look, those are the people washing their rugs at the river”.  Luckily, my mom is into that kind of stuff.  She will get equally as excited about visiting a new grocery store as she would about seeing the Eiffel Tower - so that worked in my favor.  And the rug washing, well she was ALL about that.  I had this old rug of ours that had been sitting on our balcony for months (because I was too lazy to take it downstairs to throw it away) that had a giant red stain on it that would not come out.  (Seriously, I tried everything).  Even after it had been rained and snowed on, my mom was convinced that the rug was salvageable with a good ole scrub at the river.  After studying the ways of the river washers and scouting out a perfect spot, we hauled the rug out.  Once we got to our spot and began mimicking the routine of the other washers, we realized we had a big problem.  Everyone else had these special rug brushes and pine soap that seemed to do the trick, and all we had was my dish scrubber and dish washing soap.  In attempt to act like we knew what we were doing, we hid the soap inside our bag and began scrubbing.  Except we couldn’t fool the lady next to us.  She saw right through our act.  Fortunately, she took pity on us and let us use all her gear while she was waiting for her rug to dry.  She even taught us the ways of the Finnish rug scrub.  We scrubbed that rug like mad until we couldn’t scrub anymore.  Then we waited all day to return to see if our hard work had paid off.  And it did!! I’m not going to say that the rug is as good as new, because if you looked hard enough (ok, you don’t even have to look that hard), you can still see a little discoloration.  But we just shoved that part under the couch and pretend it’s not there.  What would I do without mom to save the day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we took the train from my small, sweet town of Joensuu to the big city.  I’d been to Helsinki a number of times before, but you just can’t beat it in the summertime.  Especially when you spend the day at one of the many islands off the coast, like we did.  It was a bright, sunny and warm day that we took the ferry out to Suomenlinna and spent the day exploring the island and enjoying the weather.  It was perfect.  Although Suomenlinna is one of Helsinki’s most popular tourist attractions, it’s still Finland, so really not that touristy at all.  We found a place on the rocks to watch all the crazy people plunge into the ice water.  And because I’m kind of, maybe just a little bit competitive, I decided that I wanted to feel how cold this water really was.  I mean, if they’re doing it, I can do it.  As I started walking to the water, my mom, in true mom fashion, warned me to be careful on the moss, “It’s slippery”, she said.  &lt;em&gt;Yeah, yeah.&lt;/em&gt;  When I got to the edge of the dry rocks and put one foot on the first mossy rock, I was reminded that moms are usually right.  I slipped and fell right into the water.  So instead of just touching it with my hands, like I intended, I got a little more of the full experience.  Luckily, I wasn’t very far in and I didn’t hurt anything, so we just laughed about it for a good long while. That&amp;#39;s really why I did it, for the laughs.                       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/05/Mom-comes-to-Finland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/05/Mom-comes-to-Finland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Rome</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/pinkshades_vines.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/Collusium_tourists.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/Collusium.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/horse_meredithandscott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/flowerandwindow.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/laundry.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/vinesanddoor.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/rooftops.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/Vatican+buildigns.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/Vatican.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/statues.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/raining.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/skyline+from+Vatican.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/08.05.2014/street_flowers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rome seems like such a long time ago.  I guess it’s because we’ve been so many places since then.  The words that come to my head when I think back on our time in Rome are: hot, gelato and ancient.  I think that pretty much sums it up.  The daily routine went something like this - visit ancient building and/or church, marvel at how old and amazing it is, start getting really hot, escape to a restaurant for some AC, walk around some more, get hot again, eat gelato, eat pizza or pasta, repeat.  Mmmm…gelato.        &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/03/Rome.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/03/Rome.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Paris (&lt;em&gt;and summer in Finland&lt;/em&gt;)</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/builldings_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/building_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/man_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/selfie_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/notredame_)2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/street_notredame.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/grafiti_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/scottandparents_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/boat_meredithandscott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/car_chez.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/lawn_people.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/flowers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/paintings_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/monalisa_sculptures.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/ceiling_kenny.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_castle.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles_fountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/me_versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/scottandkenny_statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/Scott_Versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/versailles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/eifel+tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/eifeltower_kennyandbarb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/group_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.31.14/Eifel+tower+at+sunset.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of those who have prayed, hoped and wished for warm weather to make its way to Finland, thank you, it has.  Now if we could work on a little AC up in here, that’d be really cool (no pun intended). I am so thankful for and loving all this warm weather and sunshine that we’ve been getting, really I am.  Everyone is happy, people are out and about and picnics are happening all over the city.  It’s the best.  But when it’s 80+ outside and you have to be inside, with no AC, well let’s just say if it weren’t for the mosquitos I’d be sleeping in the forest.  When the wind blows our door closed, I sprint to prop it back open to prevent an immediate pool of sweat and suffocation.  I have my fly swatter (thanks mom) ready at all times in case one of those annoying creatures tries to sneak their way through the open windows and doors.  But I know that sooner than I care to admit the chilling winds will be back again and open windows won’t even be an option, so I’m going to turn that fan on high and keep reminding myself that it’s better than frozen eyelashes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a little over a month ago we took a trip to Paris for a week with Scott’s parents.  I’m going to blame the fact that I’m just now writing about it on the mere three weeks that I’ve spent in Joensuu since the beginning of June AND my little motivation to do anything that involves my legs sticking to a chair while staring at a computer.  Yep, that’s my excuse.  My idea of Paris was pretty much the same one that is portrayed on TV.  Beautiful, wonderful, romantic…just about everything perfect squished into one city.  There’s so much hype around the city that I thought there was no way it could live up to my (and many people’s) expectations.  But as cliché as it sounds, I did kind of fall just a little bit in love with the city.  The museums, churches and Eiffel Tower are all amazing, but what I really loved was the everyday kind of stuff.  Like the millions of cafés lining every street, filled with people enjoying the weather and good company.  And the parks, or just dots of green, for people to bring their picnics of baguettes, cheese and a bottle of wine (yes, that actually happens in real life).  Oh, and all the buildings.  I just couldn’t get enough of the white-grayish old buildings that give the city it’s relaxed, romantic feel.  It also didn’t hurt that we had near perfect weather the entire time we were there, which really makes everything better.  I don’t know what it is about the city. You can do nothing except sit at a café and people-watch, and at the end of the day you still feel like you’ve had a pretty solid day.  But that’s what’s so great about it. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/31/Paris-France.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/31/Paris-France.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Gdańsk, Poland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/boat_building_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/buildings_river.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/monument.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/Monument_church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/musicians_streetperformer.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/slanted_builings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.09.2014/beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up at 5:00 am, rolled out of bed, stumbled downstairs to pick up our carefully packed breakfast and began our journey to Gdańsk.  The first 2 hours on the bus were pretty silent.  Occasionally you could hear a short mumbled conversation, but for the most far it was silent, with heads bobbing up and down, trying desperately to get more sleep.  As we arrived in Gdańsk, heads began to perk up and eyes were peeled open to take in the new city.  Our first stop was a boat ride and tour of some of the historical WWII sites.  Seeing the city by boat was a fun new perspective as we watched people enjoying the warm sun and the colorful waterfront buildings pass by.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a big helping of pierogi (Polish dumplings) for lunch, we spent some time walking around the city, marveling at the beautiful churches and mesmerizing buildings.  Gdańsk is known as the capital of amber, with tons of street vendors displaying an array of jewelry made with the Baltic gold, so of course we couldn’t leave without some time spent shopping.  Our last stop, before heading back, was a quick trip to the beach on the Baltic Sea.  The beach was packed with people lounging in padded beach chairs, under umbrellas and a few brave souls who ventured out to the frigid water.  We left Gdańsk beat from the long, action-packed day, while simultaneously craving more time in the lively port town.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised with all that the city had to offer from the rich history, the cheerful old town and the lovely beaches.  I couldn’t help but think about what a perfect weekend getaway destination it would be.       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/09/Gdansk-Poland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/09/Gdansk-Poland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Toruń, Poland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/rooftops.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/rainy_street.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/flowershop_rain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/castles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/building_angel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/angel_roof.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/balcony_flags.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/classroom.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/colored_buildings_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/market.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/minibeer.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/flower_copernicus.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/outthewindow.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/07.02.2014/streets_two.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, YAY we’re back in Joensuu!  The past month has been full of fun times and great memories, but I sure was ready to be back in my own bed.  The first two weeks of the trip I was in Toruń, Poland working with students from three other countries on an intensive summer course.  The topic was building intercultural awareness in teaching English as a foreign language.  We arrived late Sunday night after a 4.5 hour train to Helsinki, 2 hour flight to Warsaw and then a 4 hour bus ride to Toruń.  Then early Monday morning we were up for the beginning of ten long days in class (don&amp;#39;t worry, we managed to squeeze in some time for fun).  There were nine other students from UEF that went on the trip, so I got to make some pretty great friends as well.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about Poland.  Go there.  Seriously, it’s such an interesting, beautiful country filled with so much history.  In Toruń there was a wonderful Old Town filled with ornate, colorful buildings that I could just stare at all day (maybe that’s why I have so many pictures of them).  And because we were studying with Polish students, we also got to learn a lot about Polish culture. For instance, what I would call ‘lunch’ they refer to as ‘dinner’ and it’s eaten at around 1 pm.  The meal generally consists of three courses and starts with a soup, then you have the entrée, which is usually some sort of meat and potatoes, and then a dessert.  Later you have ‘supper’ which is around 6 pm and is generally some form of sandwich.  Being in Poland, we followed the same daily meal schedule.  I always find it interesting to learn about other food cultures.  I think you can tell a lot about a culture from how and what they eat.  We also learned a little about Nicolaus Copernicus, who is the pride and joy of Toruń.  There&amp;#39;s a statue of him in the center of the old town and the univeristy, where we were studying, is named after him.  As our welcoming gift, we all got Nicolaus Copernicus zip drives!   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we were in class a lot, there were still plenty late nights hanging out with new friends from Spain, France, Poland (and of course, Finland).  That was the best part of the trip.  Just talking, laughing and being with those people.  After two weeks of cramming in a ridiculous amount of work and play, I was completely worn out, but it was so so worth it.           &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/03/Torun-Poland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/07/03/Torun-Poland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Market Day</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/booths.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/flags.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/fish.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/leaves.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/chef_salmon.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/romeo_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.18.2014/boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mother Nature really pulled through this weekend.  Clear skies and rising temperatures made for a pretty perfect market day.  The first traditional fish market in Joensuu was held on Saturday where vendors sold fresh fish, homemade jams, wooden handicrafts and lots of other goodies.  We sat outside eating our crucified salmon and all our winter woes were forgotten.  There’s just something about outdoor markets that makes me smile.  I don’t know if it’s the warm weather that generally accompanies them, the smell of freshly cooked food or the community feel to the whole event, but it sure makes for a solid afternoon.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t want to disappoint anyone by skipping over the weather report, so here it goes, today was &lt;strong&gt;hot&lt;/strong&gt;.  I know you’re thinking, &lt;em&gt;you mean like you only had to wear one pair of wool socks kind of weather?&lt;/em&gt;  Nope.  Like shorts and sandals and sunbathing kind of weather.  Seriously.  The city was crawling with people soaking it all up.  I’d say about 50% of the people we passed were carrying ice cream cones (including me).  Every pier we passed on the way home was occupied by picnic-ers.  We bought a fan.  These are the signs of summer.  I’m still a bit hesitant to leave the house without gloves and a jacket, I just feel naked without them, but I’m sure pretty soon I won’t be giving them a second thought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and the last, &lt;em&gt;but definitely not the least&lt;/em&gt;, glorious thing to report, we ate barbecue today.  I’m not talking about Finnish BBQ, which really just involves cooking anything over an open fire, I mean like a legit pulled pork sandwich.  In the middle of downtown Joensuu, there is a man from Florida that cooks up some serious Texas-style barbecue.  I was tempted to run around with my sandwich introducing everyone to the deliciousness of real BBQ so they could see what they’d been missing out on all this time.  Instead, I sat in the scorching sun with BBQ sauce all over my face and for a moment I felt like I was back in Texas.  Funny how food can do that to you (&lt;em&gt;or is that just me?&lt;/em&gt;)                    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/18/Market-Saturday.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/18/Market-Saturday.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>May Day</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/Balloons.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/People_balloons.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/Lake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/church_pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/stage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/05.03.2014/VappuuPicnic.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyvää Vappua! Happy May Day! We&amp;#39;ve had quite the busy week over here celebrating.  Vappu is the second biggest holiday celebration in Finland (first being Midsummers).  I&amp;#39;ve never seen so many people out in Joensuu – I didn&amp;#39;t even know that many people lived here.  Although May Day is officially May 1st, the festivities ran throughout the entire week.  We started the week with the &lt;em&gt;flying flags&lt;/em&gt; event at the university, where we each wrote about our experiences in Finland on the back of our country&amp;#39;s flag.  Then we let them go together to demonstrate what the exchange students bring to Finland.  The next day we went on a bus tour of Eastern Finland.  We stopped at various places to explore and socialize, then we were back on the bus to the next stop.  On Vappu Eve there was a parade of students from the university to an island across town.  In Finland, all students have different colored jumpsuits according to their major.  They collect badges from different events that they take part in and cover their jumpsuits in them.  On special occasions (Vappu being one) all the people that have graduated from basic school (high school) wear their graduation caps proudly.  It&amp;#39;s really a big deal to be able to show off your cap.  After the parade, people gather at the island where there is music playing and they hang out with their friends.  People continue partying wayyy into the night, since the next day is a national holiday.  On the actual day (May 1st), everyone gathers in the city center where there are vendors selling May Day balloons and streamers, a vintage car parade and plenty of socializing.  As the day goes on, people begin to make their way  to the island to have a picnic with their friends and family.  Although it wasn&amp;#39;t exactly picnic weather, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m talking 35 degrees&lt;/em&gt;, we enjoyed spending time eating with our friends.  All the Vappuu activities may have gotten in the way of a little school work this week, but I can&amp;#39;t miss out on the culture, right?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that every time I start to talk about the &lt;em&gt;amazzzzingly&lt;/em&gt; wonderful weather in Finland, it comes back to haunt me.  Remember last week when I was raving about how perfect the weather was... well I take it back.  It has snowed at least three days since then.  &lt;em&gt;Not cool, Finland, not cool.&lt;/em&gt;  They say that warm weather is coming, but I&amp;#39;ll believe it when I see it.    Yesterday we spent a good amount of time outside, when it suddenly began to snow.  I looked at a Finnish guy near us with what I&amp;#39;m sure was a “&lt;em&gt;you&amp;#39;ve got to be kidding me&lt;/em&gt;” face.  And his apt response was, “&lt;em&gt;It&amp;#39;s Finland, what can I say?&lt;/em&gt;”.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/04/May-Day.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/05/04/May-Day.html</guid>
                </item>
        
</rss>