<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Coats and Kahvi</title>
        <description>Meredith and Scott&#39;s Adventures in Finland</description>
        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://coatsandkahvi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                <item>
                        <title>Ski Break</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/03.01.2014/bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have Spring break, we have Ski break.  Both occur in March and are all about taking a little time from school to enjoy the outdoors.  Other than that, they have nothing in common.  Spring break is swimming pools, swim suits and sun.  Ski break is snow ball fights, snow shoeing and of course, skiing.  (Ok, I just noticed that they all start with S&amp;#39;s too...so there&amp;#39;s that).  I&amp;#39;m all about these sorts of icy outings and I feel like I&amp;#39;ve been a pretty darn good sport about the winter, but I&amp;#39;m going to go ahead and call it.  I can not fool my Texas brain into thinking we&amp;#39;re still in December.  It knows better.  It knows that this is the time to start breaking out the shorts and eating outside.  This snow just isn&amp;#39;t going to do it for me anymore.  I&amp;#39;m on board for it coming back in about 8 months.  But now, it&amp;#39;s time to stop this madness.  It&amp;#39;s been real.  Needless to say, we are not headed for the slopes next week.  We&amp;#39;re boarding the train headed south.  Literally.  We&amp;#39;re going to Helsinki.  Unfortunately it&amp;#39;s not exactly beachy there either, but we&amp;#39;ll take what we can get right now.  If you could direct any heat waves that you find in this general direction, we would greatly appreciate it.          &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/01/ski-break.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/03/01/ski-break.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Cold Natured</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/showshoeing_wheatgrass.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/people_frozenlake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/showshoeing_icehole.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_snowmobile.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoeing_tinytree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/snowshoes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/branch_houses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse_licking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.21.2014/horse_smiling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the days go by, I learn more and more about the Finnish culture.  I know that we&amp;#39;ve lived here for almost 6 months now, but it continues to fascinate me.  For one, Finns come alive in the winter.  It&amp;#39;s like someone flipped a switch and everyone suddenly sprang to life.  When the days get down to 20 or below, you can see the smiles on their faces and hear the excitement in their voices.  &lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt;, they say, &lt;em&gt;a proper winter&lt;/em&gt;!  They use words like &lt;em&gt;fresh&lt;/em&gt; to describe freezing temperatures.  I guess when winter takes up a majority of the year, you learn to embrace it.  No, they don&amp;#39;t embrace it, they &lt;em&gt;thrive&lt;/em&gt; off it.  All year they are waiting until the conditions are right for skiing, ice hockey, skating, ice fishing and all their other favorite winter activities.  They will tell you that the best sauna is the one when you can take a break from the heat to roll around in the snow (with no clothes on).  Now, I don&amp;#39;t want to make any over-generalizations about the entire population.  I have met a Finn that wasn&amp;#39;t a fan of winter, but I&amp;#39;d say those are few and far between.  Most of the time, you will find them enjoying the outdoors during these snow-covered days.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don&amp;#39;t know if I quite thrive  off these northern temperatures yet, I have learned to embrace them.  I get to try so many things that I&amp;#39;ve never done before, like snowshoeing.  The other day a group of us went on a snowshoeing trek on and around a peninsula in Joensuu.  It took a little while to get used to waddling like a duck in the shoes, but soon it came naturally.  When we got to the lake our guides told us that we were going to cross by walking &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the lake.  I was a little hesitant at first because I didn&amp;#39;t totally trust that the water was frozen and would be able to hold my weight (plus 10 other people), but Finnish people usually know what they&amp;#39;re talking about when it comes to nature, so I went for it.  In the distance there were people snowmobiling, ice fishing and generally just enjoying an afternoon on the lake.  Being completely new to all this cold weather stuff, it was still kind of crazy to think about an entire lake being frozen.  Oh, and the sun peeked through the clouds for a couple of minutes.  That&amp;#39;s enough to lift my spirit for days.  It was a great way to spend an afternoon and when I got home I was exhausted.  While we were out there I didn&amp;#39;t feel like it was strenuous, but I guess 3 hours of snowshoeing will take it out of you.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I know that everything I write about revolves around it being cold, but that pretty much sums up our lives right now.  &lt;em&gt;Cold and winter.&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/21/cold-natured.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/21/cold-natured.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>feeling like home</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.10.2014/tree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.10.2014/branches.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/02.10.2014/bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in the thick of winter over here.  Maybe that&amp;#39;s why I haven&amp;#39;t posted in a while.  Not because we&amp;#39;ve been in hibernation (as I predicted in my last post), it has been quite the opposite actually, I think it&amp;#39;s because we&amp;#39;re really getting settled in now.  We have routines, schedules, and everything feels so normal now.  Like this is our home.  It no longer feels strange to be &lt;em&gt;carless&lt;/em&gt;.  In fact, it was a weird feeling riding in a friend&amp;#39;s car the other weekend.  When the temperature gets up to the 20&amp;#39;s, we celebrate – I have actually said out loud, &lt;em&gt;it feels great outside today!&lt;/em&gt;  Never in my life would I have guessed those words would come out of my mouth, when there is snow on the ground and I am covered in three layers of clothing.  We cook every meal at home.  At first we were forced into this due to the lack of restaurants nearby (&lt;em&gt;or really just period&lt;/em&gt;), but now I&amp;#39;m really getting into it.  I look forward to making the next meal and am becoming quite territorial in the kitchen (I&amp;#39;m working on it).  We have great friends who we get to hang out with every week.  That really makes living anywhere enjoyable.  We share our different customs and holidays with each other, like a little international family.  Last weekend we celebrated Chinese New Year with some delicious, traditional dishes and the other day I learned how to make tortilla española, &lt;em&gt;Mmmm&lt;/em&gt;.  This weekend we celebrated Super Bowl Sunday (&lt;em&gt;that&amp;#39;s a holiday, right?&lt;/em&gt;).  Since we figured it wasn&amp;#39;t worth staying up to watch the game in the middle of the night, we postponed our viewing party.  We replayed the game,  even though we already knew the outcome (the commercials and halftime show are where it&amp;#39;s at).  And as expected, there was a continuous stream of questions about this barbaric sport Americans&amp;#39; lives revolve around for half of the year.   &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/10/feeling-like-home.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/02/10/feeling-like-home.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Hibernation Mode</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.20.2014/ice+swimming.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.20.2014/meredith_scott_iceswimming.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I go back and look at pictures or posts from, say, October or November, I laugh at the fact that I thought it was cold then.  &lt;em&gt;What a joke!&lt;/em&gt;  But I do think I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; realize what everyone meant when they said it was going to get much, much colder.  They meant that your breath would freeze your hair to your scarf, your fingers would burn, your nose would run to the extent that you could no longer feel it.  They meant that all you would crave is a hearty soup and some hot tea.  They meant that when you are forced to wear three layers (pants and jackets) to walk five minutes to the grocery store and when sleeping at school sounds like a better alternative than riding your bike home...that&amp;#39;s when you know it&amp;#39;s cold.  So in case you&amp;#39;re wondering, we will be in full hibernation mode for the next month and a half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this is going to contradict my previous statement about being in hibernation, but I guess I&amp;#39;m not really made for &lt;em&gt;full&lt;/em&gt; hibernating, even in the coldest of weather.  Some friends invited us to go to the Polar Bear Club for some ice swimming over the weekend.  It was not an easy decision to make.  To start, because it would take us 30 minutes to get there, and that in itself sounds like torture in this weather.  Then we would voluntarily be subjecting ourselves to swimming in a hole cut out in the frozen river.  None of this really sounded inticing, except for the fact that it would get us out of our apartment to see other people.  &lt;em&gt;Soooo, we went.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes like this – sauna, swimming, sauna, repeat.  The idea is to get really hot in the sauna and then when you can&amp;#39;t take it any longer, you go cool off in the ice cold water.  The river was about 30 feet from the sauna.  I knew if it didn&amp;#39;t go straight in and I gave myself time to think, it wasn&amp;#39;t going to happen.  So when I got to the point when I couldn&amp;#39;t take the heat of the sauna any longer, I marched straight down to the river and immediately got in.  When my foot first hit the water, while walking down the ladder, I thought, &lt;em&gt;this is not so bad&lt;/em&gt;.  Then I lowered my entire body in and froze.  When the water pierced through to my bones, I wanted to scream.  But it won&amp;#39;t let you.  You are left with no voice.  Your adrenaline is the only thing that allows you to swim to the other ladder to expel yourself from the water as fast as humanly possible.  As soon as you get out, your voice comes back and you can finally say, &lt;em&gt;AHHHHH, that was sooo cold&lt;/em&gt;!!  Then for the next couple minutes you feel great.  Like you could stand outside, in the 7 degree weather, in your bathing suit, all day.  After that feeling wears off you realize you most definitely could &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; stand out there any longer, much less all day, and you proceed to walk (probably closer to a run) back to the sauna.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I despise being cold, I can&amp;#39;t say that we&amp;#39;ll never do it again.  After all, it is just one of those things you do here during the wintertime.  And since we still have a good amount of winter ahead of us, we might as well embrace it.   &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/20/hibernation-mode.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/20/hibernation-mode.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Tornio and Kemi</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/yellow_building.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/tornio_church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/scott_icehole.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/meredith_scott_icehole.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/icecrack.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/boats.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/meredith_scott_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.04.2014/kemi_church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to and following New Year&amp;#39;s Eve we spent some time visiting two other cities in Lapland. Tornio is a small town that shares a border with the Swedish town of Haparanda. There wasn&amp;#39;t much to do in this small town, but it was kind of fun to walk right over to Sweden. Oh and a bonus to that is we went to a Swedish IKEA (&lt;em&gt;score&lt;/em&gt;). Most of the time IKEA is a nightmare because you generally go to buy one thing and you end up spending your &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; day there due to the endless maze of a store. However, when you are in Tornio and you are wandering around trying to find something to do, preferably indoors, walking slowly through an IKEA isn&amp;#39;t half bad. (Plus we just wanted to say we&amp;#39;d been to an IKEA where it all began). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were there we also saw one of the oldest wooden churches in Finland, built in 1686, and went to a fake Tex-Mex restaurant. The person writing for Lonely Planet must not be from Texas because what we experienced was quite possibly the furthest thing from Tex-Mex. The jalapeño poppers weren&amp;#39;t even spicy.  &lt;em&gt;What is that??&lt;/em&gt; We actually had our first encounter with reindeer at this said Tex-Mex restaurant. After that we ate it another three times over the course of our trip in the form of, reindeer soup, reindeer burger and sautéed reindeer. I think it&amp;#39;s safe to say that we enjoyed it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stay in Kemi was a little more exciting (though it doesn&amp;#39;t even come close to the huskies).  Kemi is a port town that is known for its Snow Castle and Ice Breaker ship.  Unfortunately, neither of these things were open yet. We did get to see the beginnings of the Ice Castle though, which look pretty amazing. When it&amp;#39;s finished you can book a room inside the castle where it&amp;#39;s like -18 degrees Celsius.  Apparently it&amp;#39;s also a fairly popular spot for people to get married or honeymoon in the winter (if we had only known...). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting things we did while we were there was walk on the frozen sea. There was a hole in the ice about 15 feet from shore that looked man-made, so we figured it had to be safe to walk on. It was a little risky, as we could have very well fallen through the ice and frozen to death, but fortunately we lived to tell about it. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/04/Tornio-and-Kemi.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/04/Tornio-and-Kemi.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Rovaniemi, Finland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/village.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/artic_circle.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/snowman_temperature.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/darktrees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/toys_tree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/meredith_snow.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/running_dogs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/dog_sled.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/sleighride.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/post+sleigh+ride.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/scott_dogs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/puppies.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/01.03.2014/snowtrees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/83318822&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;889&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our New Year&amp;#39;s Eve plans, as usual, were left to the last minute.  (We like to live on the edge).  Joensuu was a ghost town for the Christmas break and all flights, to just about everywhere, were jacked up for the holidays.  We knew we had to get out and do something or the darkness would swallow us up (&lt;em&gt;and because I get really antsy&lt;/em&gt;).  So after exhausting several options, we made the decision to travel to even more darkness and snow.  The bright side of this is that Santa would be there and he can brighten even the darkest of days, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt;  Joulupukki, as the Finns call him, has a village that sits on the Arctic Circle, just north of Rovaniemi.  He has a post office where you can write yourself letters to be sent or have Santa himself send you one.  He has a workshop, &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt;, where you can buy many of the trinkets that his elves make.  There&amp;#39;s a Santa restaurant, café, and everything else you could imagine.  But the real reason that we went (don&amp;#39;t tell Santa) is for the huskies.  These are not your average huskies.  These puppies are masters of the sleigh.  We opted for an hour long sleigh ride. When we got to &amp;quot;Husky Park&amp;quot; we were informed that there was a snow problem and we may not be able to go (cue extreme disappointment).  But we soon found out that one of the women working there was going to take us out, WAY out, into the woods to a family that raises and trains the dogs for our ride.  We were super pumped.  Even more so when we learned that we would be &lt;em&gt;leading&lt;/em&gt; our own team of dogs.  I had imagined we would both just be along for the ride.  Little did we know Scott would be the leader (well other than the lead dogs, that is).  If that was the only thing we had done the entire time we were there, it would have been worth it.  The experience was unforgettable. The dogs were amazing.  We learned how they were trained and the different jobs each of them had on the team.  I was in awe of how good they were.  Oh, and then to top it off, we got to see some tiny husky babies. &lt;em&gt;I died&lt;/em&gt;. Just about the cutest things I&amp;#39;ve ever seen.  I apologize for the exessive amount of dog photos, but it could have been way worse.  And, I mean, if you don&amp;#39;t like pictures of dogs, &lt;em&gt;what&amp;#39;s wrong with you?&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it back to Kemi just before midnight and rang in the new year at the Old Gringo.  2013 was really good to us and I have a feeling 2014 is going to be a pretty great year too. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/03/Rovaniemi-Finland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/01/03/Rovaniemi-Finland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Helsinki, Finland</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/church_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/blackandwhite_building.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/church_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/christmasmarket.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/kuusi.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/streetcar.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/yellowchurch.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/meredithandscott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/church_swans.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/fishmarket.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.27.2013/pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After countless times passing through, we finally got to spend a little time in Helsinki.  We went straight from several days of luxury in Switzerland to two nights in the smallest apartment ever.  &lt;em&gt;And we thought our apartment was small.&lt;/em&gt; The bathroom in this place could barely fit one person at a time, literally.  You could brush your teeth, use the toilet and take a shower, all at the same time.  Luckily, we didn&amp;#39;t spend much time inside or I might have gone crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main objective for this trip was to visit as many Christmas markets as possible.  We hit up three and got a good fill of Christmas spirit.  Since Joensuu is not exactly a booming metropolis, we decided to get our Christmas shopping done in Helsinki.  All of the markets had various stands that sold homemade good and treats, but each one was a little bit different from the others.  Glögi, the Finnish version of mulled wine, is found everywhere around Christmas.  It&amp;#39;s traditionally served with almonds and raisins, in the actual drink.  I was initially hesitant about nuts in my drink, but it ends up being a nice little snack when you&amp;#39;re finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have really loved living in and visiting some of the smaller towns around Europe.  I think it has forced me to take a look around and appreciate the little things.  It&amp;#39;s nice to feel like we live in the middle of the forest.  Whenever I&amp;#39;m in the city center, I always stop and think real hard about anything else I need to do/get while I&amp;#39;m there because if I forget something, &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt; it better be worth an hour long bike ride.  But I was raised in the city.  Deep down at my core, I&amp;#39;m a city girl.  So while we were in Helsinki, this surpressed city girl in me was doing cartwheels and flips.  I loved getting to try all the fun restaurants and cafés.  I loved that no matter where we were there was a store/restaurant/market/people around us.  We went to brunch for the first time since we&amp;#39;ve moved and it was deeeeelicious.  Oh how I miss overly priced food with fancy names.  My mouth is still watering just thinking about the mounds of food that we devoured.  It filled my compartment designated for big city things.  But truthfully, I missed Joensuu.  I was so happy to be back to our little apartment where the only thing we can hear is the loud sneezer that lives next door.  It&amp;#39;s nice to have some quiet time too.    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/27/Helsinki-Finland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/27/Helsinki-Finland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Adelboden, Switzerland | Part II</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/redshutters.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/hikingtrails.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/scotthiking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/houses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/homeonahill.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/house_mountains.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/tree_carvedtree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/meredith_mountains.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/scott_logs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/meredith_scott_hiking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.24.2013/cambrianhotel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our exciting encounters with the mountains via snowboards, we spent our last full day exploring them on something a little more familiar.  There was a hiking trail near our hotel that took us to see some pretty mesmerizing views.  We first walked through the cutest neighborhood that I&amp;#39;m convinced we&amp;#39;ll live in some day (just like every other place we visit).  The houses all had names written on them and they all looked like they would have the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; fire place inside.  Towards the end of our hike it started to snow.  Much to our surprise, Switzerland was warmer than what we are used to in Finland, so the snow was a welcomed treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two important things that we learned: everyone in Switzerland is trilingual (at least where we were), so we&amp;#39;ve really got to step up our game.  Also, I learned that you should be really sure that an egg is boiled before you try to crack it (&lt;em&gt;important life lessons&lt;/em&gt;).  Our first morning at breakfast I made it pretty clear to everyone around me that I had yet to learn this lesson.  I was really sure that this egg was boiled, &lt;em&gt;why would you serve an un-boiled egg???&lt;/em&gt;  So I tried to crack it.  It was really hard and wouldn&amp;#39;t crack on the table.  So I squeezed with all my might.  And then it cracked.  All. Over.  All over my shirt, all over my pants, all over the floor and all over my food.  It was quite a scene.  Needless to say, I avoided the eggs for the remainder of the trip.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all Switzerland was pretty amazing.  I could have stared at those mountains all day.  We were so lucky to get to spend our honeymoom amongst them.    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/24/Adelboden-Switzerland-Part-II.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/24/Adelboden-Switzerland-Part-II.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Adelboden, Switzerland | Part I</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/slopes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/mountains+in+the+distance.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/scott_chairlift.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/brownmountains.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/chairlifts.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/adelboden_chairlift.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/meredithandscott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/lunchandmountains.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/mountains_in_the_sun.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/darkmountains.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.23.2013/christmastrees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idea of the perfect honeymoon had always been a relaxing week on the beach, laying out in the scorching sun with little umbrellas in my drinks.  But since our recent move forced us pretty far north in the world, we felt like a warm beach was just too far away for a December trip, so we decided to embrace the winter.  Our minds were made up when Scott found an advertisement for a hotel wih an infinity pool looking out over the Swiss Alps - sign me up!  It really was everything we imagined (from the picture).  Skiing/snowboarding, a wintry hike and lots and lots of pool time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our journey began when our Finnish speaking skills failed us, yet again, and we were forced to walk to the train station in the snow/ice.  An hour pulling/pushing/dragging luagge through the ice qualified as my exercise for the rest of the year.  I was not a happy camper, starting from about three minutes in.  From there it took us a train, a plane, &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; train (with one transfer), and a bus to get us to this quaint Swiss town, but it was so worth it.  (I&amp;#39;d probably still be at the train station without Scott&amp;#39;s supreme navigating skills).  The people in Adelboden were so friendly and everyone spoke English (small victories).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect maybe skiing, with it being Scott&amp;#39;s first time and on some pretty narrow/steep slopes, was not the best honeymoon activity.  (The Swiss definition of &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; was a little different than ours).  We spent our first day with me trying really hard to be a good and patient snow board instructor and Scott not really feeling like I was succeeding at that.  Then I took a pretty serious tumble which left me partially crippled the rest of the trip.  At least these will be stories to entertain our children with some day.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/23/Adelboden_Switzerland.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/23/Adelboden_Switzerland.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>the frozen world we live in</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/trees_fog.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/tree_sign.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/berries.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/meredith_tree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/frozen+trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/factorysmoke.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/white+smoke.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Snow&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/12.13.2013/white+trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few photos from this last week of frozenness.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/13/our-frozen-world.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2013/12/13/our-frozen-world.html</guid>
                </item>
        
</rss>