<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Coats and Kahvi</title>
        <description>Meredith and Scott&#39;s Adventures in Finland</description>
        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://coatsandkahvi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                <item>
                        <title>St. Petersburg</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/canal+to+church.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/mosaic_palace.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/horse+and+carriage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/church+of+our+savior+on+split+blood.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/St+Peters+cathedral.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/nesting+dolls_flat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/portrait+in+front+of+church_canal.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/2015.01.17+St.+Petersburg%2C+Russia/signs_fuzzy+hat.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip to St. Petersburg came about through my teaching practice.  Our partner university is in Russia, so the program was designed so that our second practice would take place there.  I found out about this trip at our first program meeting when we got to Finland.  It had been a crazy, whirlwind of a week trying to get settled in a new country so I was a little taken aback when I heard about it (and not in a good way).  I wasn’t even used to this whole idea that I was going to be living in Finland for the next two years and &lt;em&gt;you’re sending me to Russia??&lt;/em&gt;  Needless to say, it was just my overwhelmed, irrational self that freaked out a bit in that moment and I soon built up lots of excitement about the trip.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a planner at heart.  I love looking forward and making plans about what we’re going to do, where we’re going to go and how we’re going to do it.  Checking things off my to-do lists - yep, it’s the best.  I realize that sometimes I do this to a fault and this was one of those times that I was forced to learn that lesson the hard way.  I was ready to start checking things off my list in January (and we weren’t going until October), but some of the other people, the ones that could make things happen, did not seem to share my urgency.  In fact, they had quite the opposite plans.  They were going to wait until the very last minute to issue all the paperwork so we could apply for our visas.  &lt;em&gt;It stresses me out just thinking about it again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we were, a little over a month away from our trip, applying for our visas in Helsinki.  And we were prepared.  From previous experience with visa applications we knew that we needed to double and triple check all the required documents so that everything would go smoothly, and we did.  We’re standing there, in the application office, in front of the woman carefully checking all of our stuff, holding our breath.  Then it came - &lt;em&gt;ok, everything is ready, your visas will be sent to you be next week.&lt;/em&gt;  What WHAT!!  We left the office, fist pumping the air and high fiving like we had just won the lottery.  &lt;em&gt;We did it, we’re going to Russia!!&lt;/em&gt; Then reality quickly set in and I realized that we had left our passports in the office.  So we casually knocked on the door and informed the lady that we had accidentally left our passports with her.  &lt;em&gt;Yes, and I will send them back to your next week.&lt;/em&gt;  Hm.  Now that’s going to be a problem.  You see, we are leaving tomorrow on a little trip to Sweden, Norway, Denmark, England and Ireland…and I think they’re going to want us to have our passports.  And just like that we were walking out, with all of our documents in hand, and told to come back when we could leave our passports.  All our hard work right down the drain…at least for another month.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, because I am writing about our trip, we were successful in finally getting our visas and everything else slowly but surely fell into place.  The three weeks we spent in St. Petersburg were full of all kinds of confusing, unfamiliar, and unforgettable moments, but my favorite one of all was eating with babushka.  One Sunday afternoon one of the girls in my program took us to her grandparents flat outside of St. Petersburg for a traditional Russian meal.  I was pretty pumped about the whole thing because I love trying local cuisine, especially when it’s home-cooked.  On our bus ride there, we were warned that her grandparents didn’t speak any English.  The only words I knew in Russian were hello, thank you and goodbye, which wasn’t going to get us very far.  When we walked into the very small, modest flat, we were immediately greeted by a huge smile and lots of words that we didn’t understand.  She ushered us into the living room which clearly had been set up with a nice table setting just for us.  The conversation started slow, with introductions and basic questions you ask when meeting someone new, and my new friend translating everything we said to each other.  And then came the food, and with that a flood of conversation and laughter around the table.  Babushka (Russian for grandmother) led the conversation and instigated fits of laughter with everything she said.  At one point she asked Scott what he did for a living and he responded, not going into detail, that he worked with computers for a U.S. company.  &lt;em&gt;Soooo, you’re a spy?!&lt;/em&gt;  she asked, with a sly smile on her face.  &lt;em&gt;Babushka!!&lt;/em&gt; - my friend immediately scolded her and we all had a good laugh.  By the end of our time there we had accumulated hand knit socks, a traditional Gzhel ceramic horse and one of her beloved postcards of Russian art.  It was so special.  I will never forget how warm and generous she was, inviting strangers into her home and spoiling us with delicious food and showering us with gifts.  And I will always think of her when I am curled up on the couch in my multi-colored socks.   &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2015/01/19/St_Petersburg.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2015/01/19/St_Petersburg.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>New Year + Geneva</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/bus+on+the+bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/boat+on+the+lake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/top+of+a+castle.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/door_flower+boxes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/Lake+Geneva+from+church+roof.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/Kendall_Will_grass+recliner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/door_pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/fiddleplayer_kendallandwill.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/meredithandscott_flags.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/mountains_swan+lake.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/sailboats_fountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/swan_walking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/11.04.2014+Geneva/group+hiking.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back!  To Finland and to blogging.  With the last several months of travel, family and friends, updating the blog got pushed to the back burner.  But with our return to Finland, we’re starting to get back into the swing of things.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several travel posts which have gotten backed up, starting with Geneva.  Three weeks after we got back from Ireland we left to meet our good friends, Kendall and Will, on the tail end of their Europe trip.  It was just a brief stay in Geneva, but so so worth it.  You can go anywhere with these people and have the time of your life, they seriously make everything fun.  But this city, &lt;em&gt;wow&lt;/em&gt;, gorgeous.  Everything was postcard worthy.  Well, everything besides the red-light district, where we stayed.  Let me explain.  When we were looking for a place to stay, months before, we looked everywhere.  Geneva is not exactly the cheapest place in the world, so we scoured the internet to find a place in our budget.  Kendall &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; found one, sent it to all of us to approve, we checked it out, looked good, so we booked it.  So then it’s about a month away, Scott and I are sitting around in Ireland and I’m suddenly curious about where exactly we are staying when we get to Geneva.  I put the address in my phone and it pinpoints a place in France.  So I double check that I have the address right.  Yep.  &lt;em&gt;Hmmm&lt;/em&gt;.  Text to Kendall - &lt;em&gt;Hey, can you send me the address of our hotel because I think I have the wrong one.  It says it’s in France.&lt;/em&gt;  Moments later I get a text back - &lt;em&gt;What?!? Mine says that too!&lt;/em&gt;  After a frantic search and realization that we could get a refund, we realized that it was on LAKE Geneva.  Turns out that’s not only in Geneva (&lt;em&gt;word to the wise&lt;/em&gt;).  Long story short, we found one hotel, IN Geneva, that was within our price range and close to the area that we wanted to be in.  We had a read a little something about there being some &lt;em&gt;ladies&lt;/em&gt; around this hotel, but at this point that didn’t even faze us.  So a month later, when we’re walking through the adorable city of Geneva to our hotel, I was immediately a little taken aback when I saw the short shorts (it was definitely not warm enough for those).  And then it came back to me.  &lt;em&gt;Ooooohhhhhh, yeah&lt;/em&gt;.  I shot a quick glance at Scott and he knew exactly what I was thinking.  So I guess there are some not so nice areas too, but that’s what gives it character, &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to the pretty parts.  We took the train to Lutry one day for some wine tasting and although it was not exactly what we expected, the town was everything you could wish for in a little Swiss town.  Despite our best efforts to research before we went, we didn’t have a ton of information about how thing whole wine tasting thing was supposed to work here.  One tip we read said that we should just go around knocking on doors and asking for wine.  So you can&amp;#39;t blame us if we were a little skeptical about how that was going to go.  When we got to Lutry we took the approach of asking random people on the street and in shops, where we could go to taste wine.  Every response consisted of pointing and &lt;em&gt;ummm, there is a place down/up the street/a couple streets&lt;/em&gt;.  So we wandered.  Luckily, Lutry is a great place for aimless wandering.  It’s a small town right on the lake with breathtaking views.  &lt;em&gt;What more could you ask for?&lt;/em&gt;  Wine.  We came for wine.  So we continued our search.  On one of the final tips from a friendly shop owner, we found what I’ll equate to a wine tasting room.  We walked up to the bar, expecting a set tasting that we could order, and found no such thing.  So we proceeded to describe to the bartender what we were looking for.  &lt;em&gt;Oh, I can do that&lt;/em&gt; - was the response.  &lt;em&gt;Perfect&lt;/em&gt;.  So we sat and waited for the wines.  He came, placed the wine glasses on the table, and very kindly described them for us and answered all of our questions.  Then when he left we looked at each other.  There were three wine glasses, with three different wines, and there were three of us.  Not to be picky here, but we are just used to getting a “tasting” each, which means each person gets to taste several wines.  So we politely asked the bartender if we could have two more, as in tastings.  He looked at us, furrowed his brow, paused for a second, and said (in a tone that was confused by the ridiculousness of the request) &lt;em&gt;why don’t I just bring you some more glasses so you can split the wine?&lt;/em&gt;  Oh, yes, of course, that’s a much better idea.  &lt;em&gt;Crazy Americans&lt;/em&gt;.         &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the time was just blah.  You know, like boat rides, hiking, delicious fondue, more wine, that kind of stuff.  I won’t bore you with all the details.    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2015/01/14/Geneva.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2015/01/14/Geneva.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Ireland Travel Tips</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/Ireland+Travel+Tips/Mountains_Lighthouse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EAT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Everything we ate in Ireland was pretty heavenly.  We spent most of our time in small towns so there were only a limited number of restaurants to pick from, but I don’t think you can go wrong.  Seafood on the west coast is abundant.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The Long Dock&lt;/u&gt; (in Loophead): This the restaurant that we were looking for when we ran into the cute little Irish children riding their bikes.  They serve tons of locally caught seafood.  The seafood chowder is uh-mazing (Scott ate seafood chowder at every restaurant we went to and he vouches for this).  Make sure to check out their craft beer list!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ashe’s Bar &amp;amp; Restaurant&lt;/u&gt; (in Dingle): Another great seafood restaurant in the heart of Dingle (embrace the seafood).  The first time we tried to go for lunch and it was packed, which is always a good sign.  We made sure to come back extra early the next day to get a table.  If you order the lobster they take you over to their tank and let you pick out which lobster will end up on your plate!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Idas Restaurant&lt;/u&gt; (in Dingle): This would be a great choice if you were in the mood for a slighter fancier (and more expensive) restaurant.  If you get there before 6:00 you can order from their early bird menu, so I would recommend making plans for an early meal if you’re going for dinner (this was not a problem for my dad).   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/Ireland+Travel+Tips/Dingle_sheep+grazing.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STAY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The west coast of Ireland is all about the B&amp;amp;B’s.  You can find some really great, affordable places in all of the small towns. Plus, you get to enjoy a traditional Irish breakfast and get insider tips from the owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Waters Edge B&amp;amp;B&lt;/u&gt; (in Kilkee):  We started out with this winner of a Bed and Breakfast on our first night.  The inside is so cute and the rooms are fantastic.  It looks out over the water so you get to fall asleep to the sounds of the ocean.  Kilkee is a really small town so you only have to walk about 10 minutes to get to the few restaurants and shops in town.  We only stayed one night here and we spent most of the day in Loophead, which is definitely worth the trip.         &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Duin House B&amp;amp;B&lt;/u&gt; (in Dingle): The couple that owns this B&amp;amp;B was so warm and welcoming.  They greeted us with tea and crumpets (I don’t really even know what crumpets are, I just couldn’t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; call them that).  They provided us with maps and gave us great recommendations of things to do while we were in Dingle.  The rooms have everything you need AND there are sheep next door.  So you will awake with a lovely wake up call from the sheep (it really adds to the whole experience).    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ocean View B&amp;amp;B&lt;/u&gt; (in Cahersiveen): This B&amp;amp;B was nothing fancy, but was perfect for a one night stay.  We arrived too early for check-in, but our host was very accommodating and gave us some suggestions of things to do for the next few hours.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/Ireland+Travel+Tips/Dingle_boat+and+houses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPLORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Kilkee &amp;amp; Loophead&lt;/u&gt;: We didn’t actually do much other than eat in Kilkee.  We mainly chose to stay there because it seemed to have more options and was a bigger town than Loophead.  The main attraction here is the Loophead lighthouse and cliffs.  We chose to stop here instead of Cliffs of Moher because it was more on our route and I read than it had less of a tourist crowd.  It was humbling experience to stand on the edge of the cliffs, looking down at the vast ocean.  You can also take a short tour of the lighthouse where you will learn about its history and how it is still in use today.  While you’re in Loophead, take a walk through the town and have lunch at one of the family owned restaurants.  If you’re staying in Kilkee, you could just take a half day to explore the town of Loophead.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Dingle&lt;/u&gt;: This was the biggest town that we stayed in on the coast and the one that we spent the most time in.  We spent about two days here, which seemed to be just the right amount of time to get a good taste of the town.  The first day we drove along the “Dingle Way”, which is a big loop around the area with several points of interest along the way.  You could easily spend an entire day on this, taking your time at all the different points along the way.  There’s so many places on the drive when the view changes and you’ll just want to stop to take it all in.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town of Dingle is really cute too.  There’s many different art galleries and craft shops that you’ll want to take a peek in.  We probably spent half a day just walking around looking at everything.  Also, this area of Ireland is one of the most highly populated areas of Irish speakers.  (We learned that outside of Ireland the language is called Gaelic, but within Ireland they refer to it as Irish).  If you’re driving along the Atlantic coast, I highly recommend spending some time in Dingle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Cahersiveen&lt;/u&gt;: Valentia Island is just off the coast of Cahersiveen, which has some good hiking and sightseeing.  It was really foggy the morning that we went so we didn’t get to see as much as we would have liked, but what we did see was incredible.  The other thing that we would have &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; liked to do was hike Skellig Michael.  Skilling Michael is another small island in the Atlantic Ocean where a Christian monastery was founded somewhere between the 6th and 8th centuries.  The island itself is highly affected by the wether conditions in the Atlantic, which is why we were unable to go while we were there.  It’s not an experience for everyone, as the hike up the rock seems to be pretty intense.  But if you’re looking for an adventure, and the boats are running while you’re there, you should look into it.  I still want to go back there someday.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/Ireland+Travel+Tips/shrine_two+perspectives.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTRAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Rent a car.  From what I’ve read and seen, there’s not a very extensive public transportation system in Ireland, especially along the coast.  It makes life so much easier because you decide when you want to move on to the next town and when you need an extra few hours.  If you’re not used to driving on the left side of the road, it will take some getting used to, but completely do-able (so I’ve heard, I didn’t actually do the driving).  Take the scenic route from town to town, there’s some incredible view along the way where you’ll want to stop and take pictures or just rest for a bit.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 16:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/27/Ireland-Travel-Tips.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/27/Ireland-Travel-Tips.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Ireland | Part II</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Island+construction.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Vines.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Dad+climbing+the+fort.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/side+of+castle_field.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Dad+hiking_door.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/cows.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Cow+guards.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Island+cliff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/lighthouse_two+angles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Lighthouse+in+the+distance.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Atlantic+Ocean+waves.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Dad+and+Meredith_Island.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/flowers+cliff_meredith_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Island+mountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Island_cliffs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Blarney.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Blarney+house+surrounded+by+trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/kissing+Blarney+stone.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.25.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+II/Inside+Blarney.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we left the lively town of Dingle, our next stop as we headed south was Cahersiveen.  We didn’t even know how to pronounce the name of the town, much less what to do once we got there.  Fortunately, the owner of our Bed &amp;amp; Breakfast gave us the low down on everything we needed to know once we got there.  Cahersiveen is a super tiny town, but off its coast is Valentia Island and a bit further into the Atlantic is Skellig Michael.  Valentia Island has an interesting history (it was the place where the first transatlantic cables operated between Europe and North America), along with its diverse landscape, which make it a great place to explore.  We decided to tackle the island one morning before heading on to our last stop of the trip.  When we started our drive it was so foggy that we could hardly see 10 feet in front of us, which didn’t bode well for all the amazing views we had been promised.  We pressed on anyway.  We stopped at all the different points of interest on our map and eventually got to the lighthouse.  We parked the car and made the trek down to the peninsula.  When we got close we could see there was a sign hanging on the closed gates.  &lt;em&gt;Not a good sign.&lt;/em&gt;  We finally got close enough to read that the lighthouse was closed due to weather.  The sky was dark, the fog was still holding up and the wind was howling pretty fiercely.  Although I was slightly bummed about not getting to go into the lighthouse, being that close to the wild, angry ocean somehow felt even more exciting.  I don’t know what it is, but being outside when the weather is so intense (when you’re somewhat prepared for it) gives me this thrilling rush.  It feels like I’m pushing myself up to the edge and looking down a steep cliff.  Then just when I feel like I’ve stayed there long enough to feel a small sense of accomplishment (or uncomfortableness), I walk away to a warm, dry car.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finished our sightseeing around the island, we took the scenic route to Cork.  I’m not kidding when I say this route was the most scenic of all the scenic routes.  It was also quite possibly one of the most windy routes I’ve ever taken (&lt;em&gt;and I thought I had grown out of that car sickness thing&lt;/em&gt;).   Even during the times when I had to lay my head down and close my eyes, I forced myself to peek out the window every now and then because I couldn’t risk missing any of the jaw-dropping views.  I made a mental note of some of the places that I wanted to come back and visit someday (Killarney National Park, I&amp;#39;m talking to you).  I mean, I knew Ireland had some pretty places, but it was so much more than I expected.  There’s so many places to see and things to do that I didn’t want it to end.  But I told myself that I wasn&amp;#39;t saying goodbye forever, and someday I’d be back for more.                    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/25/Ireland-Part-II.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/25/Ireland-Part-II.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Ireland | Part I</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Loophead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Meredith_loophead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Loophead+lighthouse_two+angles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Green+field.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Mountain+in+fog.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Meredith+and+Scott_field.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Kilkee+at+sunset_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Kilkee+at+sunset.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle_green+field.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle_oil+rig.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+port.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle_pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+cliff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+Way_Meredith+and+Scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Scott_beehive+sign.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle_above+the+beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+beach_cows+at+the+cliff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Motorcycle_Meredith+and+Scott_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+Way+landscapes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle_sheep.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Dingle+sheep_two+perspectives.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Ring+of+Kerry_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Ring+of+Kerry_Dad_Dingle+pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Ring+of+Kerry.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Scott+looking+down.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/10.02.2014+Ireland+%7C+Part+I/Scott_Dingle+beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our week in England, we popped over to Ireland for the next week.  At this point in the summer I had done so much planning for our previous trips that this one kind of got put on the back burner.  I booked places to stay and had an idea of some of the things we could do in each town, but it wasn’t put through my typically extensive planning regimen.  Lucky for us, Ireland turned out to be the perfect place for that type of minimal planning.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our first day, we drove out to the town of Loophead for lunch and planned to make a stop at the lighthouse.  Like many of the towns along the west coast, Loophead is a small town with more sheep than people (I don’t know if that’s actually true, but it sure seemed like it).  You would think that would make it really easy to find your way around.  &lt;em&gt;Wrong.&lt;/em&gt;  Unless you happen upon two little Irish children with fiery red hair and the most adorable accents you’ve ever heard, riding their bikes along the same dirt street that you are driving on, you might be driving in circles for a while.  We stopped to ask the kids for directions and I fully expected them to have no idea what we were talking about, much less be able to give us perfect directions to the restaurant, but that’s just what they did.  &lt;em&gt;Ye can take yer first left at the end of the street, den ye will see the main street and the restaurant will be on yer right.&lt;/em&gt;  It was too much.  I couldn’t stop talking about how ridiculously cute they were.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Irish coast is completely stunning.  Everywhere you look there are the most dramatic cliffs, mountains and fields.  One of my favorite moments was when we were driving along the coast in Dingle and we stumbled upon a beach tucked into the bottom of a cliff.  I desperately wanted to get down onto the beach so I called for a pitstop.  The view was unreal.  Waves crashing in front of you, huge rocks creating secret alcoves scattered around, and then gazing upward, were sheep and cattle grazing at the edge of the cliff.  The wind was blowing so hard that it was almost hard to see at times, but that made it all the more thrilling.  Scott braved the water while the rest of us held on to our rain coats and shouted to be heard over the roaring winds.  We didn&amp;#39;t stay for long, but the time we spent on that little beach is something that I&amp;#39;ll never forget.    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/14/Ireland-Part-I.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/14/Ireland-Part-I.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>London &amp; Brighton</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/London+bridge_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Royal+Palace_Angel+statue.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Beig+Ben_street.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/guard_flag.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Marching_Palace.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Tower+of+London_close+up.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Dad_tennis+court.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Dad_Scott_Tottenham+game.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Meredith_Scott_Tottenhamgame.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Tottenham_fans.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Dadandme_Brighton.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Brighton_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.23.2014/Brighton_ferris+wheel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything’s funnier in a British accent, don’t you think?  I’m that person that turns around and giggles every time someone says “Cheers!”, even when it’s the 274th time I’ve heard it in a week.  But you know what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; gets me…little British children.  I mean, can you think of anything cuter than a three year-old telling his &lt;em&gt;mummy&lt;/em&gt; that he thinks going to the zoo this afternoon is going to be &lt;em&gt;quite lovely&lt;/em&gt;?  That’s because there isn’t.  Nothing tops that.  Our days were filled with practicing of our own British accents every chance we got, which was &lt;em&gt;quite often&lt;/em&gt;.  I’m not sure if everyone else got quite the kick out of our constant impersonations as we did though.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much history in London, and all of England, you could be there for months and still not see everything.  We tried to see all the major tourist sites, while making sure we penciled in plently of time to explore slowly (ie., our weekend in Brighton).  It was so fun wandering around London with my dad on his first trip to Europe; we had some good quailty father-daughter time.  I think this trip may have hooked him.  He&amp;#39;ll be back to Europe again.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, I’ve decided that I’m going to start adding some “tips” to our travel posts.  They’ll be some of our favorite things that we did/ate while we were there and maybe some helpful suggestions, so that others can learn from our mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;LONDON TRAVEL TIPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We stayed in a neighborhood called Hackney, which is in East London.  The area is more “up and coming”, meaning there’s some nicer areas right next to some not-so-nice areas.  Hackney has some really nice restaurants and shops and it’s cheaper than staying in the center of London, but if you’re planning on going into the center everyday then I’d probably stay a little closer.  The Tube has easy and convenient connections pretty much everywhere, but it can add some time to your day if you’re going far, especially during rush hours. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best EATS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;The Clapton Hart&lt;/u&gt;: Really good pub food and atmosphere.  They only have a few things on their menu, but they’re all spot on.  I recommend the Bean Burger. We went here twice during the 5 days we were in London, if that tells you anything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Yum Yum Thai Restaurant&lt;/u&gt;: We had SO much food here and it was all delicious.  But maybe don’t order a Seafood sampler and an entrée each, unless you’re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hungry, then you should, because your stomach and tastebuds will thank you.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;El Olivo&lt;/u&gt;: My dad says these were the best tapas that he’s ever had.  I don’t know how many times he’s actually had tapas though, so I’m going to vouch for them too.  They were darn good.  And what are tapas without sangria? &lt;em&gt;Get it.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Thing(s) We Did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;The Parliament House&lt;/u&gt;: I’ll admit, I thought this tour was going to be really lame (I’m pretty particular about tours), but it was actually very interesting.  We did the audio tour and I’d say it was definitely worth it.  It was very well organized and not very crowded (compared to some of the other touristy places). We learned a lot about the history and current happenings of the Parliment.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Football Match&lt;/u&gt;: If you&amp;#39;re into football (soccer) and have a chance, go to a match. It&amp;#39;s quite the experience, the hardcore/rowdy fans really get you into the spirit and you get a little taste of the strong culture around the sport.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Tips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Remember that England likes to be a little unique and has different outlets than the rest of Europe, so make sure you check that you have the right adapters when you go (i.e., be smarter than us).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;BRIGHTON TRAVEL TIPS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Regency Lansdowne Guest House&lt;/u&gt;: Mike, the owner of the B&amp;amp;B, was so incredibly kind and accommodating and prepared a yummy breakfast every morning.  The rooms were very nice and Mike provides you with everything you need…even outlet adapters, for those, &lt;em&gt;ahem&lt;/em&gt;, forgetful travelers.  The house is actually located in Hove, but Brighton and Hove are neighboring towns situated right next to each other.  We walked from our B&amp;amp;B in Hove all the way to the Brighton Pier (and we weren’t huffing and puffing when we got there). An extra plus is that the beach is just a 2 minute walk down the street! You can see it from the steps of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best EATS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Archipelagos Taverna&lt;/u&gt;: Some good Greek food can be found here.  I got a Greek salad and an order of baked white beans.  I know, it doesn’t sound all that enticing, but my husband and dad practically ate all the beans off my plate, that’s how good they were.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Thing(s) We Did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Take a walk along the beach! We started in Hove (from our B&amp;amp;B) and strolled down the shore, stopping to listen to outdoor karaoke and watch the street performers, until we got to Brighton Pier.  Then we cut back up through the town, winding through the side streets decorated with millions of shops.  Seriously, &lt;em&gt;millions&lt;/em&gt;.  Then, come evening time, buy yourself a bottle of wine and some sandwich fixin’s and make your way back out to the beach and enjoy the sunset over the water.  It’s all about the beach here.         &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Tips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you are looking for a weekend escape, this is the place for you.  There’s not many &lt;em&gt;sites&lt;/em&gt; to see, but there’s plenty of restaurants, shopping and shoreline waiting for you.  We didn’t experience the nightlife, but it looked and sounded like it was pretty lively, at least on the weekends.  Cute little town overall.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/04/London-and-Brighton.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/10/04/London-and-Brighton.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Copenhagen | Round Two</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.20.2014/houses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the thing, the picture above, it’s actually from the first time that I went to Copenhagen with my mom.  This time around we were still traveling with our friends, Kevin and Debrán, and well, the weather was not all that great.  It was pretty chilly and it rained practically the entire time we were there.  That’s not to say that we didn’t have a great time, it’s just that I didn’t really take any pictures.  This time around it wasn’t so much about the sites we saw or even the food we ate (although it was still amazing), the best part of our time in Copenhagen actually revolved around a foosball table.  I’ve never really been a big fan of foosball, probably because I’ve never been very good at it, and it just seemed kind of dumb (probably because I never won).  But Kevin and Debrán wound up with a foosball table in their flat, so after dinner our first night, we decided to give it a try.  After Debrán effortlessly scored the first goal, like she’d been secretly training all her life, we couldn’t stop playing.  I don’t know if it was the dreary weather, or the fact that by game two we all had been nicknamed according to our style of play, or maybe it was the super competitiveness coming out in all of us.  Anyway, we were all hooked.  I’m sure we woke up the neighbors with our fits of laughter and the occasional scream at our teammates, the tiny plastic ones.  So that’s what happened every night, a foosball rematch, until one of the teams barely squeaked out a win (&lt;em&gt;oh, it’s not over yet&lt;/em&gt;).  And it was the best ending to a really great trip.     &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/20/Copenhagen-Round-Two.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/20/Copenhagen-Round-Two.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Bergen</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/islands.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/group_hike.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/hike_overlook.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/oldtown.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/rain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/meredith_scott.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/trains_buses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/group_fjord.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/fjord.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/ferry_meredith_debran.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/fjord_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/mountain_bird_green.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/scott_kevin_debran_mountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/ferry_debran_kevin.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/dock.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/townonthemountain.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/meredithscott_boat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.17.2014/waterfalls.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day we got to Bergen it was pouring rain and pretty darn chilly.  Scott and I came completely unprepared, with no rain jackets and barely any warm clothing.  We had gotten used to the nice warm weather we’d been having way too easily and forgotten that these places require jackets and scarfs for most of the year.  Our traveling buddies, however, came far more prepared than we did.  Which shouldn’t have come as a surprise since they’re always far more prepared than us (&lt;em&gt;that’s why we’re friends&lt;/em&gt;).  We made the decision that we weren’t going to let the rain get in our way of seeing this Norwegian city though.  After all, Bergen has over 230 days of annual rainfall (&lt;em&gt;we found out once we were there&lt;/em&gt;).  So we trudged out into the city with wet clothes and smiles on our faces (sort of).  One of the things that our host warned us about (but definitely not the most shocking) was the high cost of eating at restaurants in Norway.  Most locals cook at home to keep costs down and rarely eat out.  So we followed her advice and went to the fish market to buy our dinner.  After gathering all the supplies to make dinner, we took the short cut back to our place.  This is the other &lt;em&gt;shocking&lt;/em&gt; thing that our host warned us about.  Across the street from the apartment that we were renting, was a well known drug park.  Everyone knew it, even the police, and apparently they had made the decision to leave all the druggies be, as long as they kept to the park.  We were warned that we would see all kinds of &lt;em&gt;crrrrazy&lt;/em&gt; stuff going on in the park.  &lt;em&gt;It’s like your own private show, right outside your window,&lt;/em&gt; she explained, laughing. We all laughed with her.  Then when she left we looked at each other, completely stunned.  Not exactly the kind of welcoming we had imagined.  But then we laughed again, for real this time, and took the long way to the market.  Well on the way back it was raining, like really raining, and we were carrying heavy bags of groceries.  So we opted for the short cut through the park, after all, she assured us it was completely safe.  &lt;em&gt;Don’t look at them, walk fast, but not too fast, act like we’re talking&lt;/em&gt;…these were the things we reminded each other of before embarking on the 2 minute walk through the park.  &lt;em&gt;Ok, we’re almost there.  Which way is it?  I think it’s this way.  Wait, maybe it’s that way.  Just keep walking!&lt;/em&gt; - as we basically slid down a steep muddy hill, which was clearly not the path to our apartment.   But looking lost in the middle of the drug park was not an option, so we acted as if we needed a good challenge.  Sidewalks bore us.  We successfully made it back, after what seemed like 2 &lt;em&gt;very long&lt;/em&gt; minutes.  We earned some serious bravery points for that, I’m sure.  I mean, no big deal, we’re hardcore.                     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our first day there, mother nature pleasantly surprised us with lots of sun and very minimal rain.  I think that I can speak for the group when I say that the best part of our stay in Bergen was the day we took the ferry through the Sognefjord.  To get to the fjord we took a train and a bus through some of the most stunning landscapes I’ve ever seen.  The kind that that make it on postcards.  It was unreal.  But the ferry through the fjord was definitely the cherry on top.  The greenest greens and the bluest blues you’ve ever seen.  Waterfalls every time you turned your head.  Mountains coming straight out of the river, on both sides, decorated every so often with a tiny cluster of houses.  Better than the pictures.  It was, without a doubt, worth &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; walks through the drug park.                     &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/17/Bergen.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/17/Bergen.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Stockholm</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/island.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/guards_oldtown.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/apples_bikes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/groupphoto.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/park_boats.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/peopleswimming.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/scott_buildings.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/over+the+water_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.15.2014/sunset.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this next round of travels, not only did we have some exciting Scandinavian cities to visit, but we also had some of our favorite people join us!  We met Kevin and Debrán in Stockholm to start the trip and, despite their luggage getting lost by the airlines, it was a pretty great kickoff.  We decided that the best way to see the city (and save our feet) was to join the hordes of commuting bike riders.  On our first day with the bikes we took them exploring through one of the many islands which was, apparently, one of the &lt;em&gt;cool kid&lt;/em&gt; hangouts during the summer.  Stockholm is pretty cool like that.  They have all these random, &lt;em&gt;gigantic&lt;/em&gt; parks all over the place where you can find pretty much the entire population of the city on a nice summer evening.  So we followed suit and did our fair share of sitting, laying, picnic-ing on the grass, soaking up as much of summer as these Scandinavian countries offer.  Then we fantasized about buying one of those adorable houses on the water and going on bike rides everyday around the islands, picking fresh apples and maybe even building up the courage to swim in the frigid water. Yeah, I know, I do that everywhere I go.  I can’t help it, I like to dream.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/15/Stockholm.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/15/Stockholm.html</guid>
                </item>
        
                <item>
                        <title>Copenhagen &amp; Aarhus</title>
                        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/sunset+bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/mom_me_bridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/grafetti_bike.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/castles_bw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/copenhagen+from+the+top.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/momtower_tower.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/floweres.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/me_bikepath.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/porridge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/porridge_bread.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/cheers_trees.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/houses_grafetti.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/apartments.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/momandme_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/house.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/yard_momandme.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/pier.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/pier_water.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/goingdownthestairs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/rocks.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/flowers_sail.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/sailboat_bathhouse.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/blackberry_mom.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/ARoS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Meredith Scoggins&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/coatsandkahvi/09.09.2014/ARoS_inside.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denmark has definitely made its way onto my list of “places I could live”.  The food really helped give it a good shove up the list.  I still daydream about it.  Scott and I have become major porridge fans since living in Finland and Copenhagen has a restaurant dedicated SOLELY to porridge. Score! But it’s really more than just food (although that might be enough to make me move there).  Everything is just so…pretty.  They’ve really got that whole Scandinavian design thing going for them.  Copenhagen has all that you could want in a big city without feeling too big.  And when you want to escape from all the fuss of the city, well you can just have a picnic in the cemetery, like we did.  To tell you the truth, I was a little skeptical about this whole idea at first, but the first time we walked through and saw locals running, sun bathing and enjoying their lunch, I was convinced.  It’s basically a giant park.  And what better way to use such a space on a sunny afternoon, than a picnic.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people in Denmark also helped make it so wonderful.  They are so down to earth and friendly, which really worked in my favor, since I had a couple of &lt;em&gt;moments&lt;/em&gt; during our time there.  It started the first day we were in Copenhagen. After our first super delicious meal, I left my jacket (the only one I brought) at the restaurant.  We were mid-way through the Superkilen park when I realized (and panicked).  I walked just about as fast as I could, without looking like a lunatic, back to the restaurant.  Luckily, my jacket was waiting for me just inside the door.  The second time I tested the Danes was while we were walking to the canals.  On the way we decided to pop into in several boutique-y shops.  Well, I found a really nice piece of pottery and I wanted to see how much it cost.  So I picked it up.  Unfortunately there were two pieces to this particular item and I only picked up the top part.  After that, all I remember is the entire thing on the floor, in a million pieces.  (Although I did manage to see the price, which was equivalent to $100.)  First, the sweet woman working looked stunned, like she didn’t know what to do.  (Probably because nothing like that had ever happened before…oops.) Then she quickly went to clean it up and told us not to worry about it.  After helping her clean, I could not get out of the store fast enough.  The rest of the trip I had someone looking over my shoulder to make sure I wasn’t touching anything breakable, &lt;em&gt;thanks mom&lt;/em&gt;.  The last little mishap, was not so little after all.  See, I bought train tickets from Copenhagen to Aarhus. Or at least I thought I did.  And what does one do when they &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they buy train tickets? Well, they get on the train.  Turns out (after three different people tried to figure out &lt;em&gt;what in the world&lt;/em&gt; was going on with our tickets) I had bought bus tickets instead.  &lt;em&gt;Whoops&lt;/em&gt;.  But we were already on the train on our way to Aarhus.  So thankfully, the super kind ticket checker let us slide.  I told you those Danes were nice.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m pretty sure that I made such a good impression on them, soon they&amp;#39;ll be begging me to move there.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 17:05:06 +0300</pubDate>
                        <link>http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/11/Copenhagen-and-Aarhus.html</link>
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coatsandkahvi.com//2014/09/11/Copenhagen-and-Aarhus.html</guid>
                </item>
        
</rss>